Life is a beach.
Summer Rental is a comedy film directed by Carl Reiner.
Jack Chester, an overworked air traffic controller,
takes his family on vacation to the beach.
Things immediately start to go wrong for the Chesters, and steadily get worse.
Jack ends up in a feud with a local yachtsman, and has to race
him to regain his pride and family's respect.
Jack Chester, played by John Candy.
Al Pellet, played by Richard Crenna.
Scully, played by Rip Torn.
Sandy Chester, played by Karen Austin.
Jennifer Chester, played by Kerri Green.
Don Moore, played by John Larroquette.
Summer Rental is a 1985 American comedy film directed by Carl Reiner, written by Mark Reisman and Jeremy Stevens, and starring John Candy and Richard Crenna with supporting roles by Rip Torn, Karen Austin, Kerri
Green, John Larroquette, Joey Lawrence, Aubrey Jene, Dick Anthony Williams, Richard Herd, Carmine Caridi, Lois Hamilton, Frank McCarthy, Santos Morales, Pierrino Mascarino, Harry Yorku, and Bob Wells.
It tells the story of an overworked air traffic controller who is put on a five weeks' paid leave and takes his family to the fictional
resort town of Citrus Cove, Florida as he experiences hilarious mishaps and contends with an arrogant sailing champion.
An original music score was composed for the film by Alan Silvestri.
The film was released on August 9, 1985, by Paramount Pictures.
The film explores themes of rivalry, family vacation,
suffering parent, time off, run down house.
The tone is lighthearted.